Welcome to Building a Gentic Rag with Llama Index.
I'm joined by Jerry Liu, who is co-founder and CEO of
Llama Index and the instructor for this course.
Thanks, Andrew. I'm super excited to be here with you.
In this course, you'll learn about a Gentic Rag,
a framework to help you build research agents capable of
advanced tool use, reasoning,
and decision-making over your data.
For example, what if you have a set of research papers on some topic,
and you want to pull out the parts relevant to a question you want to ask,
and you get a synthesis of what the papers say.
This is a complex request that require multiple steps of processing.
Further, earlier steps of processing,
like maybe identifying a theme from one paper,
might also change the later steps that are needed,
like retrieving additional information from other papers about that theme.
In comparison, the standard rag pipeline, which is very popular,
is mostly good for simpler questions over a small set of documents,
and works by retrieving some context, sticking that into an OM prompt,
and then just calling the OM a single time to get a response.
This course will take the idea of chatting over your data to the next level,
and show you how to build an autonomous research agent.
You'll learn a progression of reasoning ingredients to a building of four agents.
First, routing, where you add decision-making to route requests to multiple tools.
Next, tool use, where you create an interface for agents to select a tool,
as well as generate the right arguments for that tool.
And then finally, multi-step reasoning with tool use,
where you use an OM to perform multi-step reasoning with a range of tools,
while retaining memory throughout that process.
You'll learn how to effectively interact with an agent,
and use its capabilities for detailed control and oversight.
This will allow you to not only create a higher-level research assistant
over your RAG pipelines, but also give you more effective ways to guide its actions.
Specifically, you'll learn how to ensure debuggability of the LLN.
We'll look at how to step through what your agent is doing,
and how to use that to improve your agent.
One additional very powerful tool is to let the user
optionally inject guidance at intermediate steps.
For example, if you see it searching the wrong document,
a little nudge to search a different document from human input,
much like an experienced manager, that's you,
giving a more junior employee a nudge to consider a new piece of information,
can give much better performance.
Many people have worked to create this course.
I'd like to thank, from Llama Index, Logan Markowicz, and Andrea Fajardo.
From dblm.ai, Dialla Ezzedine also contributed to this course.
In the first lesson, you will build a router over a single document
that can handle both question answering as well as summarization.
That sounds great. Let's go on to the next video and get started.